

Profile

Driven, detailed-oriented Software Engineer experienced in Program Management in digital media and systems engineering. I have an innate curiosity and desire to understand how things work and a passion for walking in the shoes of the end user. This has materialized in building and deploying an IOS application after I purchased my first iPhone to learning Unity after years of playing video games.

Employment History

Sr. Technical Program Manager at LinkedIn, New York

October 2019 — October 2019

Leads Media Business Platform portfolio to support a \$1.7 billion business unit and partners closely with Product and Engineering leadership to plan, staff, and execute projects.

Key Accomplishments

- Facilitated cross-functional strategy and planning sessions to form a 3
 year road map
- Managed and delivered first two phases of \$157 million incremental revenue project within first 3 months

Sr. Program Manager at LinkedIn, New York

January 2013 — July 2018

Partnered closely with engineering teams to support various deployments. Hosted regular briefings to communicate progress and road map to executive stakeholders. Hired, on-boarded, and grew New York based Global Sales Systems team.

Key Accomplishments:

- Principle systems designer on order management overhaul that drives \$170M+ in revenue potential and \$30M margin improvements by 2020.
- Led Sales Systems project portfolio to support \$750 million business unit.
- Reduced order cycle times from 7 hours to 25 minutes per deal.
- Managed and lead user stories and design for \$175M acquisition of Bizo
- Conceptualized and implemented custom software known as the 'ad sales cockpit' to simplify operations and increase efficiency with a \$1M+ in margin improvements on time saved

Campaign Planner at LinkedIn, New York

January 2012 — January 2013

Collaborated with Sales, Revenue, and Pricing teams to build, optimize, and deliver world-class advertising performance for both customers and LinkedIn.

Key Accomplishments:

Details

5163149186

dmryan711@gmail.com

Links

Linkedin

Skills

React

Agile Project Management

Express

MongoDB

Unity

Objective-C

Salesforce.com Development

HTML, CSS, JS

Excel VBA

Hobbies

Skiing, Gaming, and Traveling

 Designed and developed custom application for internal workflow optimization that ultimately automated the role itself.

Publishing Coordinator at Publishers Clearing House, Port Washington

July 2010 — January 2012

Guided clients though campaigns by providing optimization solutions.

Education

Full-Stack Web Development, Columbia Engineering, New York January 2019 — July 2019

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, University at Buffalo, Buffalo

September 2006 — July 2010

Courses

Introduction to Game Development, Michigan State University July 2016 — July 2016

Priciples of Game Design, Michigan State University
August 2016 — August 2016

Game Development for Modern Platforms, Michigan State University

September 2016 — September 2019